Dhruv Rathore

Software Developer



Resume Summary

Organized and passion for problem-solving software engineer graduate with 1.5+ years combined internship and professional experience. Fluent in Java, Restful API, PostgreSql, Spring Boot, Django and Github. Possess practical working knowledge of relational databases using PostgreSql and Agile Development.



Work Experience

05/2022 -06/2023

Executive Trainee

3i Infotech Limited, Noida, UP.

- Resolved critical software issues, ensuring smooth functionality and minimizing downtime for users.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Authored code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches.
- \rightarrow Developed reports using POSTGRESQL server.
- Integrated third-party APIs to expand application \rightarrow capabilities and improve overall performance.
- Gained valuable experience working within Advance EdTech Proiect.

02/2022 -05/2022

Internship

3i Infotech Limited, Noida, UP.

- Demonstrated strong problem-solving skills in addressing diverse challenges throughout development process.
- Participated in code reviews with experienced developers, gaining valuable insights.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.



Education

2019-2022

Rungta College of Engineering and Technology

Bhilai. CG

· Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science Engineering



Projects

All India Management Association (AIMA)-Centre For Management **Education**

- Contributed to functionality enhancement, bug fixing, and adding new features.
- \rightarrow Adding new features and conducted thorough testing
- \rightarrow Database management (PostreSql).
- Introduced updated business logics to improve performance.



Personal Info

Address

Rajnandgaon, CG, 491441

Phone

+91-8827480322

E-mail

dhruvr.3750@gmail.com

Github

github.com/dhruv37502005

Linkedin

www.linkedin.com/in/dhruvr3750



Skills

Programming Language

- Java 8
- **Python**

Java Frameworks

- **Spring Boot**
- **Spring MVC**
- * **Hibernate JPA (ORM)**

Database

- **PostgreSQL**
- MySQL

Server-side technologies

- **HTML** *
- Servlets
- **JavaServer Pages (JSP)**

Application Server

Apache Tomcat

Build Tools

Maven

Spring Cloud Eureka

Python Framework

Diango Rest Framework

Version Control

- Git Hub
- * SVN

IDE's

- **Eclipse**
- Vs Code
- IntelliJ



Languages

English



Gujarati

Hindi

Intermediate



Personal Projects and Contributions

Micro-Services-Project Hotel Rating System

- **Advance Hotel Rating System developed using MicroService** Architecture.
- Tech:- Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate JPA, PostgreSQL, Rest Template, Spring Cloud (Eureka), OKTA Auth, API Gateway, Lombok, Maven, Resilience4J and Feign Client

Online Course Management System -Baoiam Innovation Pvt

- Contributed to build a complete course and student management system developed using Django Rest Framework.
- Tech:- Python, Django Rest Framework, Social-Auth lib, Css, Html, Javascript, SqLite3, Pillow lib and Rest Api's



Training and Courses

Data Structure and Algorithms in Python

-from Jovian Bootcamp

Java Programming Fundamentals

-from Infosys Springboard Program

Microservices and RESTful APIs with Spring Boot and **Spring Cloud**

-from Infosys Springboard Program



Personal Info

Leet Code Profile

leetcode.com/dhruv3750/

Hacker Rank Profile

hackerrank.com/profile/dhruv rathor 35

Hobbies

- Reading
- Martial Arts
- Cooking